<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kube101.jeffgeerling.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kube101.jeffgeerling.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-11T17:54:47+00:00</updated><id>https://kube101.jeffgeerling.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kubernetes 101</title><subtitle>A YouTube streaming series on Kubernetes and container-based infrastructure by Jeff Geerling.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kubernetes 101 Livestream series starts Nov 18!</title><link href="https://kube101.jeffgeerling.com/2020/kubernetes-101-starts-nov-18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kubernetes 101 Livestream series starts Nov 18!" /><published>2020-11-11T16:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T16:10:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kube101.jeffgeerling.com/2020/kubernetes-101-starts-nov-18</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kube101.jeffgeerling.com/2020/kubernetes-101-starts-nov-18">&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes 101 is a new educational video series by Jeff Geerling, and the first live episode will premiere on YouTube on November 18, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff Geerling is the author of bestselling book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansiblefordevops.com&quot;&gt;Ansible for DevOps&lt;/a&gt;, and streamed a very popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2020/ansible-101-jeff-geerling-youtube-streaming-series&quot;&gt;Ansible 101&lt;/a&gt; series earlier this year on his YouTube channel. Jeff is also writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansibleforkubernetes.com&quot;&gt;Ansible for Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, and has maintained a Raspberry Pi Kubernetes cluster for many years, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pidramble.com&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Dramble&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series will cover all the basics of Kubernetes and cloud-native infrastructure, and will demonstrate how to manage containers, clusters, and applications running inside those clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-miss-out&quot;&gt;Don’t miss out!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to subscribe to Jeff Geerling’s YouTube channel and enable notifications so you don’t miss out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/JeffGeerling&quot;&gt;Jeff Geerling’s YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the ‘Subscribe’ button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the bell to set up notifications when new streams are live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first episode, “Hello, Kubernetes!” will air on &lt;strong&gt;November 18, 2020&lt;/strong&gt; starting at &lt;strong&gt;11 a.m. US Eastern&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldtimebuddy.com/event?lid=5%2C2643743%2C30%2C2147714&amp;amp;h=5&amp;amp;sts=26761260&amp;amp;sln=11-12&amp;amp;a=show&amp;amp;euid=c508febe-1657-4014-e9a5-269593354ab1&quot;&gt;see it in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All episodes will be recorded and available on-demand immediately following the live stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-is-it-for&quot;&gt;Who is it for?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series is meant for complete beginners to Kubernetes and cloud-native deployment. If you’ve dabbled in Docker, or even if you’ve never used it before, you will learn a lot about containers, Kubernetes, and cloud-native computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you have already used a managed Kubernetes service before, learn more about how everything works under the hood through this free series on YouTube!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to the series sponsor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazee.io&quot;&gt;Amazee.io&lt;/a&gt;. Amazee offers fully managed Kubernetes clusters, and they take away the stressful work of managing Kubernetes itself, so you can focus more on the software you run on your clusters. They also maintain &lt;a href=&quot;https://lagoon.readthedocs.io/en/v1.10.0/&quot;&gt;Lagoon&lt;/a&gt;, which runs on Kubernetes and lets you deploy your applications automatically, enabling powerful and easy GitOps workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">Kubernetes 101 is a new educational video series by Jeff Geerling, and the first live episode will premiere on YouTube on November 18, 2020.</summary></entry></feed>